Guide to the Paula Green papers, 1940-2013 and undated RL.11500
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Paula Green papers
1940-2013 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Green, Paula, 1927-2015
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11500
90.00 Linear Feet
Advertising executive at Doyle Dane Bernbach and Paula Green Advertising, based in New York. Collection includes correspondence, photographs, slides, audiovisual materials in multiple formats (VHS and Umatic videocassettes; audio cassettes; phono records; optical discs, audio and video tape reels, 16mm film), market research reports and financial reports, print advertisements, storyboards, musical scores, cookbooks and other printed materials. Companies represented in the collection include American Cancer Society, Burlington Industries, CBS radio, Chemstrand, Doyle Dane Bernbach, General Foods, Goya Foods, Hathaway shirts, Heinz, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Green Dolmatch, L.C. Gumbinner, New York Times, Paula Green Advertising, Quaker Oats, Seventeen Magazine, Sterling National Bank, Subaru, and the U.S. Public Health Service. Materials cover commercial products and advocacy campaigns for breast cancer awareness, self-examination and prevention, tobacco use and antismoking programs. Most materials are in English; however some items exist in French, Italian, Japanese and Spanish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General and Personal Files; Doyle Dane Bernbach; Lawrence C. Gumbinner Advertising; Green Dolmatch; Paula Green Advertising; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive at Doyle Dane Bernbach and Paula Green Advertising, based in New York. Born 1927, Los Angeles, California; BA University of California, Berkeley, 1944; Grey Advertising 1947-1948; Promotions Director, Seventeen Magazine 1952-1954; Copywriter, L.C. Gumbinner 1954-1956; Vice President, Creative Manager, Doyle Dane Bernbach 1956-1969; Creative Director and President, Green Dolmatch 1969-1977; Creative Director and CEO, Paula Green Advertising 1978-2013; One Club Creative Hall of Fame 2012; Died Dec. 4, 2015 New York.
Significant campaigns: Avis "We Try Harder"; Subaru U.S. launch; ILGWU "Look for the Union Label"; American Cancer Society (breast self examination; PAP smear test advocacy); U.S. Public Health Service antismoking campaign; New York Times "Home Delivery"; Ms. Magazine launch.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Paula Green papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union records; Leonard Sirowitz papers; Lore Parker papers; Nicole Di Bona Peterson Collection of Advertising Cookbooks; Reva Korda papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, photographs, slides, audiovisual materials in multiple formats (VHS and Umatic videocassettes; audio cassettes; phono records; optical discs, audio and video tape reels, 16mm film), market research reports and financial reports, print advertisements, storyboards, musical scores, cookbooks and other printed materials. Companies represented in the collection include American Cancer Society, Burlington Industries, CBS radio, Chemstrand, Doyle Dane Bernbach, General Foods, Goya Foods, Hathaway shirts, Heinz, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Green Dolmatch, L.C. Gumbinner, New York Times, Paula Green Advertising, Quaker Oats, Seventeen Magazine, Sterling National Bank, Subaru, and the U.S. Public Health Service. Materials cover commercial products and advocacy campaigns for breast cancer awareness, self-examination and prevention, tobacco use and antismoking programs. Most materials are in English; however some items exist in French, Italian, Japanese and Spanish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising executives; Advertising agencies; Women in the advertising industry; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Doyle Dane Bernbach Inc.; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union; New York Times; Burlington Industries, Inc.; Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.; General Foods Corporation; H.J. Heinz Company; Ohrbach's Department Store. [not LC]; Quaker Oats Company
- General and Personal Files, 1940-2012 and undated; 1
  - General, 1940-2012 and undated; 1
    - Awards, 1964-1985 (Box 1)
    - Awards--One Club Creative hall of Fame, 2012 (Box 1)
    - Awards--Pinnacle Awards, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Biographical, 1972-1988; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Biographical, undated (Box 16)
    - Biographical--Interview with Grant Johnson (University of Texas), 1997 (Box 1)
    - Biographical--Interview with Maurine Greenwald (University of Pittsburgh), 2001 (Box 1)
    - Biographical--J. Nicholas DeBonis entry, Ad Men and Women, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
    - Biographical--Who's Who, 1977-1996 (Box 1)
    - Birthday, anniversary posters, undated (Box 72)
    - Business cards, undated (Box 1)
    - Cable television clipping file, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Comments on "creative upsurge" in advertising, 1984 (Box 1)
    - The Connoisseur antique shop--Correspondence and copy concepts, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Copy ideas, lyrics, notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1965-1999; 8 folders (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1965-1999; 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
    - Correspondence--Charities, 1980-1995 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence--Dana Frank (use of union label song in book), 1998-2000 (Box 4)
    - Creative--Miscellaneous art, undated (Box 59)
    - Credentials file, 1971-1996; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Interview--Getting to Women on the Subject of Smoking, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Kansas City Art Directors--Correspondence and article on nonsmoking, 1974-1982 (Box 4)
    - Kaufman Astoria Studios, undated; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Martin Bickstein, John Glucksman "Automatic Factories", undated (Box 70)
    - Memoir--"Collaboration", undated (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous art, designs, undated (Box 71)
    - Music composition book, 1940-1941 (Box 4)
    - New York State Insurance Department v. Palisades Life Insurance Co.--Statement of Paula Green, 1974 (Box 4)
    - One Club Hall of Fame press, 2012 (Box 4)
    - Photographs, 1978 and undated; 6 folders (Box 4)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 69)
    - Photographs--Buddy Hackett, 1970s; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Photographs--Paula Green, undated (Box 5)
    - Photographs--Pearl Bailey, 1970s (Box 5)
    - Photographs--Portraits, undated (Box 5)
    - Photographs--Rockfield, undated (Box 5)
    - Photographs--Wedgwood, undated (Box 69)
    - Photographs--Women's Education Day, undated (Box 5)
    - Photographs--Zohra Lampert (Box 5)
    - Planner, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Press and publicity, 1965-1991; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Press and publicity, 1965-1991; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Press and publicity--Madison Avenue, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Press and publicity--Quotes, articles, 1969-1977 (Box 6)
    - Press and publicity--Quotes, articles, 1976-1985 (Box 69)
    - Press and publicity--Stuart Elliott article (mention of Avis), 2012 (Box 6)
    - Publicity file, 1969-1984; 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Scrapbook of Paula Green Inc. career, circa 1995 (Box 65)
    - Seventeen Magazine, 1952-1954 (Box 16)
    - Seventeen Magazine--Pamphlets, undated (Box 16)
    - Seventeen Magazine--Print advertising, 1954 (Box 72)
    - Slides, undated (Box 6)
    - Slides--Eye exam, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Slides--Fisheye (effect), undated (Box 6)
    - Slides--Marks, New York City scenes, undated (Box 6)
    - Slides--Raggedy Ann, Holly Hobbie, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Slides--Star filter (effect), undated (Box 6)
    - Slides--Store names, undated (Box 6)
    - Slides--Straight (no effects), undated (Box 6)
    - Slides--Whirlpool (spa treatment), 1989 (Box 6)
    - Testimony (Senate Subcommittee)--Childhood smoking, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Women and the American Economy (conference), 1975 (Box 6)
    - Women in the workplace clipping file, 1978-1987; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Printed Materials, 1958-2012 and undated; 2
    - A Book About the Classic Avis Advertising Campaign of the 60s (Henri Holmgren and Peer Ericksson), 1995 (Box 7)
    - ABC Sports, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Adobe Systems--Font + Function, 1991 (Box 64)
    - Ads Magazine--Hollywood Commercials, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Ads Magazine--Sex and Nudity in Advertising, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Ads Magazine--Special Report: UK vs. US, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Adweek Special Report--Cosmetics and Toiletries, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Adweek Special Report--Creativity, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Adweek Special Report--Woman Behind the Mask, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Adweek Special Report--Women in Advertising, 1983 (Box 7)
    - American TV Commercials Festival, 1959-1967; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Andrew Unangst brochure, undated (Box 7)
    - Art Direction, 1961-1963; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Asoliva: Olive Oil from Spain, 1989-1990 (Box 8)
    - Awards brochures, 1964-2012 (Box 64)
    - Bert Marcus print, 1971 (Box 71)
    - Boris Gonzalez: Products from Spain mailer, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Brooklyn Botanical Garden--A House Plant Primer, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Cable Is Not Television (Daniel Ritchie), 1983 (Box 8)
    - Caroline Jones article on minorities in business, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Catherine Feff Creation credentials (outdoor art), 1996 (Box 64)
    - Charivari (store) sketchbook, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Clara Bow, Love Among the Millionaires movie poster (1930) reproduction, undated (Box 72)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes: Stretch Jeans, Heinz Happy Soup, Paramount Chicken
    - Commercial song scores, undated (Box 68)
    - Council for American Fashion, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Cosmetics industry articles, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Deltox Rugs--The Case of the Near-Sighted Fisherman, undated (Box 8)
    - Domtar Paper brochure, undated (Box 8)
    - Émigré catalogs, 1991-1995 (Box 8)
    - Empire Silhouette: Historical Survey (Ermina Stimson; includes a paper doll), 1958 (Box 69)
    - Fendi Fur Collection, 1979 (Box 64)
    - Gerard Associates typeface list, undated (Box 8)
    - Hispanifile mailer, undated (Box 8)
    - Honoring a Commitment to the People of America: The Record of President Jimmy Carter on Women's Issues, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Hopper Paper brochures, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Hopper Paper--Sumo, 1990 (Box 64)
    - Hopper Paper--Taking Shape, undated (Box 64)
    - ILGWU calendars, 1977-1981 (Box 64)
    - Illustration (Sal Barracca and Associates), 1991 (Box 8)
    - Image Bank--A Catalog of Existing Illustrations, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Interep Radio Research--AM Radio, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Interep Radio Research--Black America, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Interep Radio Research--Marketing to Women in the 90s, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Interep Radio Research--Radio Research Primer, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Interep Radio Research--Reaching the Hispanic Market, 1991 (Box 8)
    - ITC Store (Typefaces), 1984 (Box 8)
    - Jacqueline Dedell client catalog, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Jacqueline Dedell client catalog (Artists representative), 1988 (Box 64)
    - James River Papers--An Appreciation of Planet Home, 1992 (Box 64)
    - Jill Applebaum: The Sting of Sexism, undated (Box 8)
    - JWT New York Business Development Apparatus, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Kathryn Jackson--Drafts (What If? and a Christmas book), 1973 (Box 9)
    - Lyrics & Lyricists, 1983-1993 (Box 9)
    - Marx Myles Typographic Services brochure, undated (Box 64)
    - Master Eagle Family of Companies--Toward Harmony and Brotherhood, 1972 (Box 9)
    - Mojud Hosiery--How Helen Landed Her Man (Vic Herman), undated (Box 9)
    - New York Fashion Group--Directional Fabric Colors, 1958 (Box 9)
    - New York Times Magazine--Osaka Design, undated (Box 64)
    - Newsweek--Women Who Work Survey, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Patrick Media--Poster Map: Core Asian Ethnic Market Coverage (San Francisco), undated (Box 9)
    - Recipe books and food catalogs, 1985-1993 (Box 9)
    - Richard Solomon Artists Representative, 1989 (Box 64)
    - Richling Ades and Richman--It's Still Pretty Good (work by Paula Green), undated (Box 9)
    - Sanders Printing--The Picture Book 8, 1985 (Box 64)
    - Shiseido: The Art of Beauty, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Social Climate Overview (Yankelovitch), 1981 (Box 9)
    - Solidarity, 1993 (Box 9)
    - T.D. Green poems, 1987 (Box 9)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Comparative Costs to Consumers of Convenience Foods and Home-Prepared Foods, 1963 (Box 9)
    - U.S. News and World Report Special Report: Working Women, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Urbane Publicity--Images and Imaginings, 1988 (Box 64)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University Ad Center admissions package, 1996 (Box 9)
    - When Advertising Tried Harder (Larry Dobrow), undated (Box 10)
    - Williams Sonoma Catalog for Cooks, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Woman's Choices (Yankelovitch), 1985 (Box 10)
    - Women in America (Geraldine Whitehead for Sperry & Hutchinson), 1972 (Box 10)
    - Yankelovitch Monitor, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1970-1994 and undated; 3
    - A New Leaf, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Additional Comments of Advertising Agency Creative Directors as Given to S.R. Bernstein for Use with Speech to Insurance Advertising Conference, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Advertising in the 1980s (Box 10)
    - Adweek correspondence and article drafts, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
    - Are Our Products Better than Our Ads?, 1983 (Box 10)
    - As Seen By Paula Green, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Breast Cancer/Mastectomy article, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Communication: To Whom? By Whom?, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Cosmetics: Time to Grow Up, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Dallas speech, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Fight Against Cancer (Brain 71; English and Japanese), 1971 (Box 10)
    - Here's My Beef (PC Magazine), 1985 (Box 10)
    - How I Lost My Fear of IBM and Started to Sell Personal Computers, 1984 (Box 10)
    - How to Advertise Organizations, 1978 (Box 10)
    - In Answer to Your Questionnaire re Women and Advertising (Ad Age survey), 1982 (Box 11)
    - Invisible Woman (One Club speech), 1983 (Box 11)
    - Israel Bond dinner, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Letter to New York Times on subway fares, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Mass Media Anti-Smoking Campaign Around the World, 1975 (Box 11)
    - The New Product Fizzles; The Old Product Dies: A Short Course in Resucitation, 1984 (Box 11)
    - New Roles for Advertising Beyond Marketing Products, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Play script, undated (Box 16)
    - Poems, lyrics, undated (Box 16)
    - Response to Mary Earle, Time Magazine, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Shelf Wars (Essays on cosmetics and older consumers), undated (Box 11)
    - Some Words from Paula Green on Larry Dobrow's Book on Avis, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Speech file, 1976-1986; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - The "Other Kind" of Ad: Making It Work, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Union League Club speech, 1986 (Box 11)
    - What Ever Happened to the Woman Over 40?, 1985 (Box 11)
    - What Kind of Message Do You Want to Convey?, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Why Cable Died: A Backward Look Ahead, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Women Over 40, speech to One Club, 1985 (Box 11)
    - You Can't Beat 'Em With the Same Old Schtick, 1984 (Box 11)
- Doyle Dane Bernbach (DDB), 1957-1986 and undated; 2
  - General, 1961-1986 and undated; 4
    - Ad Writers Newsletter--Bill Bernbach Copywriter Hall of Fame, 1964 (Box 12)
    - American TV Commercials Festival, 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Annual Report, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Articles and miscellaneous, 1968-1991 (Box 68)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1963-1969 (Box 12)
    - DD News--15th Anniversary, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Letter to Lore Parker, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Merger with Needham, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Paula Green interview, Marketing and Communications, 1969 (Box 12)
    - Pre-Testing Advertising, undated (Box 12)
    - Press, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
    - Review and Discussion of Advertising Testing Services, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Stockholders Meeting, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Stockholders Newsletter, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Accounts, 1957-1984 and undated; 5
    - American Viscose--Avril copy concepts, undated (Box 12)
    - American Viscose--Avril copy concepts, undated (Box 67)
    - Avis--Anecdote on Avis campaign, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Avis--Article in Brain II (Japanese), 1968 (Box 12)
    - Avis--Press, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Avis--Print advertisements, 1963 (Box 12)
    - Avis--Print advertisements, 1964-1994; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Avis--We Try Harder button, undated (Box 12)
    - Burlington Industries--Consumer Products Report, 1968 (Box 12)
    - Burlington Industries--Copy concepts, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Burlington Industries--Copy concepts, undated (Box 67)
    - Burlington Industries--Correspondence, memos, 1967-1968 (Box 12)
    - Burlington Industries--New products, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Burlington Industries--Proposal for Burlington Home Fashion Award, 1968 (Box 13)
    - CBS Radio--Press, 1958 (Box 13)
    - CBS Radio--Print advertising, 1957-1958 (Box 13)
    - CBS Radio--Print advertising, 1958-1959; 2 folders (Box 67)
    - CBS Radio--Print advertising, 1958; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Chemstrand, 1957-1959 (Box 13)
    - Chemstrand Acrilan print advertising, 1957-1959; 3 folders (Box 67)
    - Chemstrand Acrilan print advertising, 1957-1959; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Chemstrand Acrilan print advertising--Newspaper, 1957-1959 (Box 71)
      Includes ads for Chemstrand Nylon, Eversweet 1960, Gallo
    - Chemstrand Nylon print advertising, undated (Box 71)
    - Cresta Blanca Wine--Print advertising and storyboards, undated (Box 71)
    - Eversweet print advertising, 1960 (Box 71)
    - General Foods--Dream Whip storyboards, 1966 (Box 13)
    - General Foods--Dream Whip storyboards, 1966 (Box 67)
    - General Foods--La France, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - General Foods--SOS Soap Pads: Notes and correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 13)
    - General Foods--SOS Soap Pads: Scripts and copy strategy, 1968 (Box 13)
    - General Foods--SOS Soap Pads: Storyboards, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
    - General Foods--SOS Soap Pads: Wire cleaning soap research, 1966 (Box 13)
    - Goodman's Soup, 1957 (Box 13)
    - H.J. Heinz--Correspondence, legal, 1965 (Box 13)
    - H.J. Heinz--Great American Soup, 1964-1966 (Box 13)
    - H.J. Heinz--Great American Soup print advertisement, undated (Box 59)
    - H.J. Heinz--Happy Soup can labels (Disney tie-in), undated (Box 13)
    - H.J. Heinz--Heinz soup Project K (Disney co-promotion), 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - H.J. Heinz--Heinz soup Project K (Disney co-promotion), 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - H.J. Heinz--Memos and miscellaneous, 1961-1965 (Box 14)
    - H.J. Heinz--Reports, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Lane Furniture print advertising, 1958; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Lawry's Spaghetti Sauce storyboard, undated (Box 71)
    - Lever Brothers--Hero Detergent, 1967 (Box 14)
    - Lever Brothers--Hero Detergent package design, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Max Factor, 1958 (Box 14)
    - Ohrbach's print advertising, 1958 (Box 67)
    - Ohrbach's print advertising, 1958; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Post Instant Breakfast, undated (Box 14)
    - Quaker Oats print advertisements, undated (Box 59)
    - Quaker Oats print advertisements, undated (Box 67)
    - Quaker Oats print advertisements, undated (Box 70)
    - S&W Foods, 1958 (Box 14)
    - Salada print advertising, 1959-1960 (Box 71)
    - Sea Brand print advertising, 1960 (Box 71)
    - U.S. Public Health Service, 1969 (Box 14)
    - Various print advertisements, 1957-1959 and undated (Box 67)
      Includes: Charis, Cresta Blanca, Cutex, Eden Roc, French Tourism, Gallo, Goodman's, Hunter Douglas
    - Various print advertisements, 1960 and undated (Box 67)
      Includes: Lane, Lawry's, S&W, Salada, Sea Brand, Wedgwood
    - Various print advertisements, 1964 and undated (Box 68)
      Includes: Avis, Burlington, Connoisseur
    - Various print advertisements, newspaper, 1957-1959 and undated (Box 67)
      Includes: Charis, Gallo, Lily of France, S&W, Salada, Sea Brand
    - Wedgwood print advertising, 1960 (Box 71)
    - Yardley print advertising, undated (Box 71)
- Lawrence C. Gumbinner Advertising, 1954-1956; 3
  - Barbara Gould Deodorant, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Bourjois Evening in Paris, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Ciro Perfume, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Dunhill, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Dunhill Humidor print advertising, undated (Box 67)
  - Happy Feet, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Martell, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Memo introducing Paula Green to staff, 1954 (Box 16)
  - Messing Bakery, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Nectarine Vin de Rose, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Q-Tip, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Roitan cigar, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Roman Holiday, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Savarin Coffee, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Swingline, 1956 (Box 16)
- Green Dolmatch, 1950-1996 and undated; 4
  - General, 1969-1983 and undated; 6
    - 2nd anniversary skit, 1971 (Box 17)
    - 5th anniversary t-shirt mailing correspondence, 1975 (Box 17)
    - Corporate documents, 1969-1983 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1974-1977; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Correspondence congratulating Paula Green on new agency, 1969 (Box 17)
    - Directors meeting, 1974 (Box 17)
    - Helen Hubbell--Unsolicited copy drafts, 1975 (Box 17)
    - House advertisement, 1972 (Box 17)
    - House advertisement, 1972 (Box 68)
    - John Glucksman art and designs, undated (Box 69)
    - Memoranda, 1972 (Box 17)
    - Press and publicity, 1970-1977 (Box 17)
    - Slides, 1971 and undated (Box 17)
    - Slides--5th anniversary. ILGWU shoot, 1974-1977 (Box 17)
    - Some Relevant Facts About Green Dolmatch, undated (Box 17)
    - "Superman" film scene shoot, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Accounts, 1950-1996 and undated; 7
    - American Cancer Society--Advertising Age article on cigarette ad ban, 1975 (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Breast self-examination, 1969 (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Chart, Per-Capita Reduction of Cigarette Consumption, 1972 (Box 70)
    - American Cancer Society--Correspondence, 1970 (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Getting to Women on the Subject of Smoking, 1973 (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Harper's Bazaar "Breast Bazaar", 1976 (Box 68)
    - American Cancer Society--Mailers, undated (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--National Award press release, 1978 (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Photograph, American Cancer Society Awards, 1978 (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Photograph, Lola Falana, undated (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Presentation, undated (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Press, 1975-1978 (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Press, 1975-1978 (Box 68)
    - American Cancer Society--Print advertising, 1970-1972; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Slides, Lola Falana, undated (Box 17)
    - American Cancer Society--Third World Conference on Smoking and Health, 1975 (Box 17)
    - H. Hentz--Print advertising, 1973 (Box 68)
    - H. Hentz--Print advertising, 1973 (Box 70)
      Explanation of ad's circumstances on back
    - H. Hentz--Print advertising, 1973; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Harwood Canadian, undated (Box 18)
    - Harwood Canadian mounted print advertisements, undated (Box 60)